# MAUREEN CABALLERO

#### 630.854.9314

maureencab@gmail.com
public.tableau.com/profile/maureen.s.caballero#!/
linkedin.com/in/Maureen-caballero-1990a32b

# PROFILE

As a manager at Panera Bread, my favorite part of the job was analyzing data and improving business processes based on the results. I decreased our overall food cost to industry standard using data to inform my decisions. I draw actionable conclusions from complex data through my analytical mindset, managerial background, and varied work experiences.

# **EDUCATION**

#### **Nashville Software School**

Data Analytics Certification Expected Graduation Jan 2021

# **Stanford University**

Bachelors Economics, 3.4 GPA

#### Udemy

**Statistics for Business Analytics** 

# **SKILLS**

- Advanced Proficiency in Excel (Pivot Tables, VLOOKUP, Power Pivot)
- SQL, Python, Tableau, and PowerBI
- Certified Salesforce
   Administrator, through self-study
- PowerPoint
- · Agile Methodology

# **DATA EXPERIENCE**

# DATA ANALYTICS APPRENTICE NASHVILLE SOFTWARE SCHOOL

#### **JULY 2020-PRESENT**

- Active participant in intensive, real-world, project management-based training in data analytics using business intelligence visualization tools to drive business decisions.
- Gained practical experience in the analytics workflow of extracting, transforming and loading data (ETL), then building reports, creating dashboards, and presenting findings and recommendations.

#### **DATA PROJECTS**

# **MLB Historical Data Analysis**

github.com/NSS-Data-Analytics-Cohort-3/lahaman-baseball-maureencaballero

- Wrote SQL queries to extract and analyze data spanning 27 tables and years 1871-2016.
- Utilized JOINs, window functions, and CTEs to extrapolate historical data into current findings.
- Created several data stories including best Tennessee schools feeding into MLB based on number of players and average salaries, assessed how strikeouts and homeruns per game have changed over decades, and related season game wins to eventual World Championship winners.

# **Data Visualizations**

public.tableau.com/profile/maureen.s.caballero#!/ https://bit.ly/30mu0fE

- Used Tableau to visualize human resource survey results and to recommend strategies to combat attrition.
- Used Power BI to analyze bike sales and recommend actions to be taken to increase profitability.

# **UN Data on GDP and Internet Usage**

github.com/NSS-Data-Analytics-Cohort-3/un-data-maureencaballero

- Used python and pandas to examine the relationship between countries' GDP and internet usage.
- · Created scatter plots using matplotlib.
- Used agile methodologies for project management creating Kanbanstyle issues, using commits, pull requests, branch and master tracking in GitHub.

continued

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### STOCKED TO ROCK, LLC

#### Owner/Analyst, Franklin, TN

October 2015 - Present

- Research market opportunities using proprietary software; analyze Exceldata to select and source manufactured goods internationally; evaluate data to create marketing plan and materials; develop and optimize Amazon listings.
- Analyze metrics to maximize advertising budget.
- Have grown business 50% over each of past two years.
- Manage all business, accounting, and analysis aspects of \$300,000 business.

#### SEPA MUJER, SERVICES FOR THE ADVANCEMENT OF WOMEN

# Salesforce Business Process Consultant, Patchogue, NY

April 2020 - September 2020

- Set up case management system for company hotline, reducing quarterly grant reporting from two days to one hour.
- Mapped business processes to customize their Salesforce environment and streamline processes. Positively
  affected their constituent services through increased accuracy and labor savings by eliminating redundant
  data entry.
- · Developed customized reports and dashboards to aid in decision-making.
- Conducted data cleaning and import from Excel to update contact and membership information.

#### **PANERA BREAD**

# Assistant Manager, Franklin, TN

October 2015 - March 2020

- Motivated and supervised up to fifty associates to ensure a quality service experience for Panera guests, while maintaining company labor, financial, and sanitation standards for \$90,000/week cafe.
- Decreased food cost variance consistently below industry standard of 3%, through data cleaning, analysis, and coaching associates on actionable areas to reduce food cost.
- Regularly led Planet Bread, a corporate training session for three to ten new hires. Brought associates to company standard of Certified in three areas.
- Responsible for inventory, ordering of \$20,000/week, receiving.

#### **GOOD SHEPHERD CHURCH**

# Cornerstone Cafe Director, Naperville, IL

June 2012 - September 2015

- Managed all business aspects of a profitable, high-quality, full-service cafe, supervising and scheduling team of fifty volunteers and paid staff.
- Increased operational profit 30% in the 2013-2014 fiscal year through strategic menu expansion and repricing, inventory management and product sourcing, and overall improved guest experience.
- Implemented iPad Square POS system, improving volunteer ease of use, guest counter service, sales data analytics, and pricing and accounting management.

# **NAPERVILLE PROPERTIES**

#### Real Estate Rental Owner and Property Manager, Naperville, IL

2005-2013

- Utilized Excel to report and analyze data related to profitability of properties. Set up automated monthly reports for KPIs.
- Managed all business aspects of purchasing and supervising several rental properties.